*河水波澜辽阔*
*The water is wide*
*我们无法渡河*
*And we cannot get o'er*
*而我们又无双翼*
*And neither have we*
*无法飞身过河*
*Wings to fly*
*将...*
*Give...*
卡塞尔  我以为就是个小聚会
Castle, I thought this was gonna be a small gathering. I mean...
你买的食物够50个人吃了
There's enough food in here for, like, 50 people.
永远不要低估剩菜的重要性
Never underestimate the importance of leftovers--
隔夜填馅  火鸡汤
second-day stuffing, turkey soup,
微波炉加热洋芋  再扫荡一下食物银行
microwave yams, and a visit to the food bank.
还有  阿丽克西斯总会做甜点
And so that you know, Alexis always makes dessert.
派说他要做个什么小红莓调和酒
Pi said he would make a cranberry concoction of some kind.
就连我妈也会下厨
Even mother cooks something.
-虽然不是都能下咽  -我听到了
- It's not always edible. - I heard that!
知道吗  我做的...
Well, you know what? I make a...
填馅超级好吃  我爸爸的烤玉米羹也非常拿手
killer stuffing, and my dad makes a great traditional corn casserole.
好啊  而且我知道你该穿什么服装
Nice. And I know the perfect costume for you,
你就别担心了
so you don't have to worry.
服装
A costume?
我要扮演首批移民约翰·罗尔夫
Yeah, I'm gonna be, uh, settler John Rolfe,
所以不用说  你要扮他的新娘宝嘉康蒂
so you will, obviously, be Pocahontas--his bride.
阿丽克西斯拿不定主意
Alexis goes back and forth.
有时候扮清教徒  有时候又扮美国土著
Sometimes she's Puritan. Sometimes she's native American.
要看她当时的心情了
Just depends on where she is in her life.
你父亲想扮哪一方都行  不用太复杂
Your dad can be whichever. Nothing elaborate.
你们感恩节还要穿服装吗
Uh, so you guys-- you guys dress up for thanksgiving?
这不是传统吗
Doesn't everybody?
不  这是你家的传统
No, I think that's pretty special to you.
我们结婚之前我还需要了解什么
Um... so is there anything else I should know about you
关于你的事吗
before we get married?
好多呢
So many, many things.
市中心一座教堂发生凶案
There's been a murder in a church downtown.
可惜不是在大教堂啊
Too bad it wasn't in a cathedral.
那就太像T.S.艾略特的风格了
That would be so T.S. Eliot.
《大教堂谋杀案》啊  托马斯·贝克特[故事主角]
"Murder in the Cathedral"? Thomas Becket,
-都是贝克特啊  -走吧
- Beckett and Becket? - Come on.
-这么不给面子  -走吧
- Nothing? - Let's go.
-谁给个反应嘛  -谢谢
- Anyone? - Thank you.
等我们结婚的时候
You know, when we do this,
可别在红毯尽头摆具尸体
let's not do the dead body in the middle of the aisle.
好想法
Okay. Good call.
怎么回事
So what happened?
死者6点半在弥撒期间走进教堂
Well, our victim entered the church during 6:30 mass
身中数枪
with multiple gunshot wounds,
一路走到祭坛前
made his way towards the altar
然后便摔倒在地
before collapsing.
不过倒下之前还给了牧师点东西
But not before handing the priest a little somethin' somethin'.
宝宝
A baby?!
男婴  我猜他有三个月大了
A boy. I'm guessing he's about 3 months.
而且他饿了  总来摸我的胸
And he's hungry, 'cause he keeps going after the girls.
不能怪他啊  你好啊  小家伙
Well, who can blame him? Hi, buddy.
你叫什么  小伙子
What's your name, little man?
问得好
That is a very good question.
-这是孩子的父亲吗  -我们还不知道
- So is this the baby's father? - We don't really know.
但我们知道他叫卡梅隆·杜卡恩
But what we do know is his name is Cameron Ducane,
30岁  住在布朗克斯
30, lived in the Bronx.
他钱包里没有宝宝的照片
There's no baby pictures in his wallet.
他有个商务车司机执照
He's got a commercial driver's license--
大概是个职业司机
Probably drives for a living.
有个洗车券
He's got a car wash coupon,
跟莱恩一样  他把辛苦赚来的钱
and, like Ryan, spent his hard-earned money
买了彩票
on a lottery ticket.
那可是五州魔法球大奖  两亿4700万
That is the 5 state magicball jackpot at $247 million.
不买才是疯了
You're crazy not buying a ticket.
买一两张得了  你买了50张
Yeah, 1 or 2, but not 50.
我只是想增加中奖几率
I'm just increasing my odds of winning.
你是增加破产几率吧
Increasing your odds of being broke.
你知道在纽约市养个孩子
Listen, do you have any idea what it costs
要花多少钱吗
raising a child in New York city?
我不知道要花多少钱
I don't know how much it costs--
-伙计们  -你当然不知道
- Guys. - Well, of course you don't.
-伙计们  -我不是...
- Guys! - I'm not--
我们别当着宝宝的面吵架好不好
How about we don't fight in front of the baby?
联系杜卡恩的近亲
Okay, contact Ducane's next of kin.
看看这个小家伙是不是他的孩子
Let's see if this little guy is, indeed, his.
那这段时间他要去哪
And then what happens to him in the meantime?
我们会联系儿童福利机构
Well, we'll get ahold of child services...
他们会安置他  直到我们能把他还给他家人
and they'll place him until we're able to get him back to his family.
我觉得蕾妮说得对  他好像是饿了
I think Lanie's right. I think he is hungry.
你们在这儿扫尾
Um, how about you finish up here?
我找个警员
I'll grab a uniform,
跟我去给他买点东西
and we'll just go pick up some stuff for him?
你真心的吗
You really want to do that?
当然  我资质颇深  我有儿童保育的RHD
Of course. Highly qualified. I have an R.H.D. in child care.
RHD是什么
And an R.H.D. is...
"狂野帅气爹"
"Ruggedly handsome dad."
好吧  去吧
Okay. Fine. Go.
伙计  我们走
Hey, buddy... let's go.
别看她啊  走吧  我们去买冰淇淋
Don't look at her. Come on. We'll get ice cream.
知道他是在哪中枪的吗
Do we know where he was shot?
警员发现时  车还没熄火
Uniforms found it with the engine running
两边车门大开
and both doors wide open.
有人从上面向他开枪
Someone fired at him from above,
穿过车顶
through the roof.
好多血啊
That's a lot of blood.
发现少了点什么吗
Notice what's missing?
没有安全座椅
There's no car seat.
-说  -不论是怎么回事
- Yeah. - Whatever happened,
我想他并没打算开车带着个小宝宝
I don't think he planned on having a baby with him.
看不出他到底开了多久
There's no way of telling how long he had been driving.
他或许是在附近被枪击的
I mean, he could have been shot nearby...
-也可能是在很远的地方  -好吧
- Or miles away. - Right.
让警员查看交通监控录像
Have uniforms go through traffic cam footage.
看看能不能查清
Let's see if we can figure out
这车是从哪个方向过来的
what direction this car was coming from.
找到死者的妻子了  那不是他们的孩子
We found the victim's wife. It's not their kid.
我们才结婚两年
We've only been married for two years.
我们还没准备好要孩子
We weren't ready for a baby.
会是你们哪位朋友或亲戚的孩子吗
Could the baby be a friend's or a relative's?
不会  我从没见过他
No, I've never seen him before.
丽莎  我知道这不好受  但会不会
Lissa, I know this is hard, but is it possible
-卡梅跟别的女人有了孩子  -不可能
- that Cam had a baby outside of your marriage? - Absolutely not.
卡梅什么都会告诉我
Cam told me everything.
他绝不会保守那么大的秘密
He wouldn't have kept a secret like that.
好吧  他今早去哪了
Okay. Where did he go this morning?
你知道他在干什么吗
Do you know what he was doing?
他去工作了  他...
He was at work. He's...
他是一家汽车服务公司的司机
He's a driver for a car service.
-他什么时候去的  -大概昨晚十点
- When did he go in? - Around 10:00 last night.
他值夜班  11点到早6点
He works the overnight-- 11:00 to 6:00.
我就觉得不对劲
I knew something was wrong.
他总会早上7点回家
He just always comes home by 7:00.
你注意他最近有什么不寻常之处吗
Uh, did you notice anything unusual in his life recently,
有什么迹象表明他有麻烦了
anything that would point to trouble of some sort?
有
Actually, yeah.
两周前  他开始变得...
A couple of weeks ago, he started acting--
怎么说呢...疑神疑鬼
I don't know--paranoid.
他买了一个家庭安全系统
He bought one of those home security systems,
而且给家里的门都多上了一副锁
and he put extra locks on all of our doors.
-他解释了吗  -没有  他就说...
- Did he say why? - No, he just...
他只是说他爱我
Oh, he said he just loved me...
想保证我的安全
And that he just wanted me to be safe.
他受雇的豪车公司叫什么
This limo company-- what's the name?
卡梅隆  天呐  他可是我们最好的员工
Cameron? Jeez, he was one of my best guys.
人好  可靠  善良
Nice, reliable, good soul.
-怎么回事  -我们还希望你能提供点线索
- What happened? - We were hoping you could tell us.
我们知道他昨晚值了夜班
We know he worked the overnight yesterday.
他今早几点交班的
What time did he finish his shift this morning?
他没有  他昨晚的确是该来上班
He didn't. He was on the books to work last night,
-但他根本没来  -他常这样吗
- but he didn't show up. - He do that a lot?
在这儿一年半了  第一次这样
Nah, a year and a half here. That was his first time.
你注意到他工作上有什么事吗
You notice anything going on with him at work--
不太寻常的事
Anything unusual?
对了  上周有个人来过
Yeah, yeah, there was that guy that showed up last week.
小心点  伙计们  开出来吧
Watch yourselves. Guys, bring it out.
什么人
What guy?
卡梅说是他老朋友了
Well, Cam said he was an old friend, right?
但我看他们不像很友好的样子
But they didn't look too friendly to me.
卡梅看见他时脸都白了
When Cam saw him, he went pale.
于是他出去和他交谈
So he stepped outside to talk.
听起来吵得挺凶
And it sounded pretty heated.
你知道他们在说什么吗
You know what it was about?
没有  但我听到他提到了坐牢的事
No, but I heard the guy say something about going to prison.
卡梅回来时很慌乱
When Cam came back inside, he was rattled.
那个人走前告诉卡梅  他还会回来
And before that guy left, he told Cam that he'd be coming back.
那人又出现了吗
This guy show up again?
没有  但我觉得卡梅害怕他
Nah, but I got the feeling Cam was scared of him.
因为一般情况下他凌晨三点
Because normally he'd come back to the garage
会回车库休息
for his 3:00 a.m. lunch break.
但自从那人出现后
But since that guy showed up,
他就会整晚在外面
he'd be staying out all night,
好像害怕回这里似的
like he was scared to come back here.
这个人  你能描述他的外貌吗
This guy-- can you describe him?
我没看到他的脸
I didn't really get a look at his face.
但是  我记起来了
But oh, oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
他手臂上有一处纹身
He had this, uh, tattoo on his arm.
很显眼
It was pretty spectacular.
是一头露出牙齿的狼  对着月亮咆哮
It was a wolf--teeth bared-- howling at a moon.
咆哮狼纹身  还真挺具体的
Wow, a howling wolf tattoo? That's pretty specific.
如果这家伙服过刑  在监狱纹身数据库里
If this guy did time, there should be a record of it
应该会有记录
in the prison tattoo database.
埃斯波西托在查了  知道这婴儿是谁家的吗
Esposito's checking right now. Any idea whose kid this is?
没有失踪婴儿的报告
Uh, there's no reports of any missing babies.
好吧  那死者呢
Okay, how about our victim?
他之前有几张超速驾驶罚单
Well, aside from a handful of speeding tickets
除此之外没什么案底
back in the day, he's clean.
他所有的朋友都说他很沉默
All of his friends say that he was quiet,
努力工作  对妻子十分忠诚
he was hard-working, and completely devoted to his wife.
他晚上十点去上班  但没到公司
Huh. Guy takes off for work at 10:00 p.m. and never arrives.
然后第二天早上6点45
And then at 6:45 the next morning,
他出现在教堂里  中弹身亡
he shows up shot to death at a church...
还抱着别人的婴儿
holding somebody else's baby.
这八个小时内发生了什么
What the hell happened during those eight hours?
你管这叫"买点东西"
Hey, so that's "a couple of things"?
是啊  我只买了必需品
Yeah, I just grabbed the essentials,
尿布  手提安全座椅  湿巾  毛巾
you know, uh, diapers, a carrier, wipes, blankies,
奶瓶  配方奶粉  可不想让小科斯莫挨饿
bottles, formula, don't wanna little Cosmo going hungry.
-科斯莫啊  -对
- Cosmo, huh? - Yeah.
-我们又不能一直喊他"宝宝"  -为什么叫科斯莫
- We can't just keep calling him "The baby." - Uh, why "Cosmo"?
如果阿丽克西斯是个男孩  我就打算取这名
It's what I was gonna call Alexis if she was a boy.
火鸡衣服
A... turkey outfit?
-没搞错吧  -是火鸡连体衣
- Really? - It's a turkey onesie.
这可是感恩节啊
It's Thanksgiving.
很贵  但是超可爱
It was expensive, but it's adorable.
而且我说过  我门家感恩节这天会穿上盛装
And like I said, my family dresses up for Thanksgiving.
我突然清楚地看见了
I'm suddenly getting a clear and frightening visual
我未来的恐怖景象
as to what my future will look like.
卡塞尔  能让我抱抱他吗
Hey, Castle, um, mind if I... hold him?
让我体验一下
It'd be good experience for me.
-当然可以  -好
- Oh, yeah, absolutely. All right. - Good.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Ready? - Oh, yeah.
-把他的头放在那儿  -我知道
- Put his head there. - I know.
-抱低一点  这样...  -我知道
- Hold him under so that-- - I know.
他在哭  我哪里做错了
He's crying. What am I doing wrong?
尽量保持冷静  他们能感觉到恐惧
Just try to remain calm. They can sense fear.
这跟练习娃娃可完全不同
This is not at all like the practice doll.
我以为我准备好了
I thought I was ready.
-显然  我没有  -好吧
- Clearly, I am not. - All right.
天啊  我还没准备好
Oh, god, I'm not ready.
-他真的很喜欢你  -是啊
- Oh, he really likes you. - Oh, yeah.
我不知道你是否了解我的这一点
I don't know if you know this about me--
婴儿很喜欢我
babies love me.
我是婴语者
I'm the baby whisperer.
想抱抱他吗
Wanna hold him?
不想  我宁愿查清楚他是从哪来的
Uh, no. I'd rather figure out where he came from.
-当我...  -闭嘴
- Well, when a m-- - Stop.
住嘴  我知道婴儿是从哪来的  卡塞尔
Stop. I know where babies come from, Castle.
只是  不知道他哪来的
Just... not this one.
你怎么会不想抱他啊
I can't believe you don't want to hold the baby.
大家都喜欢抱婴儿啊
Everyone wants to hold the baby.
我不想抱他
I don't want to hold that baby.
监狱纹身数据库有匹配
So I got a hit in the, uh, prison tattoo database.
看看吧
Check it out.
和罗曼描述的一样
Just like Roman described it.
是啊  纹身的主人是吉米·沃夫斯基
Yep. Belongs to one Jimmy Wolfinsky--
又名野狼吉米
A.K.A. "Jimmy the wolf."
是多起银行和珠宝抢劫的嫌疑犯
Suspected in a handful of bank and jewelry jobs.
七年前  他抢劫银行时
He was arrested seven years ago
被抓  随后被判刑
and convicted when a bank robbery went south.
他两周前刚被保释
He just got paroled two weeks ago.
他和死者有何联系
Any connection to our victim?
他抢的那家银行
Well, the bank that he robbed--
吉米本可以逃走的
Jimmy would have gotten away,
但当他走出大楼时
but when he came outside the building,
他的逃亡汽车已经开走了
his getaway car was gone.
警铃大作时  吉米的同伙溜走了
Jimmy's partner bolted when the alarm sounded.
警察没抓到他  吉米也没有招供
Cops never caught him, and Jimmy never ratted.
但是  目击证人画出了
But... witnesses were able to provide a sketch
逃亡司机的草图  看起来眼熟吗
of the getaway driver. Look familiar?
那是死者卡梅隆·杜卡恩
That's Cameron Ducane-- our victim.
我们性情温和的豪车司机有过犯罪历史
Our mild-mannered limo driver had a criminal past.
看来过去的事找上了他
Looks like that past just caught up with him.
原来这是个背叛和复仇的故事
So... it's a tale of betrayal and revenge.
当吉米被抓时
Cameron abandons his partner Jimmy
卡梅隆抛弃了他的同伙  让他承担责任
when he comes down, leaving him to take the fall.
卡梅隆满怀内疚  想把过去的事情抛诸脑后
Ridden with remorse, Cameron tries to put it all behind him,
重新开始生活
start his life anew.
但是突然
But surprise, surprise,
吉米保释了
Jimmy made parole,
而他足足想了七年
after spending seven long years
如何要让自己的老搭档付出代价
thinking of ways to make his old partner pay.
难怪卡梅隆加了锁
No wonder Cameron was adding locks.
他不想告诉妻子这件事
He didn't want to tell his wife about it,
因为他不想让她知道自己的犯罪历史
because he didn't want her to know about is criminal past.
这推论很不错  卡塞尔
That's a great theory, Castle,
不过这婴儿是哪来的
except where did the baby come from?
也许...
Ah. Maybe...
我一点思路也没有
Nope, I got nothing. Hmm.
我刚和野狼吉米的保释官谈过了
I just talked Jimmy the wolf's parole officer.
吉米在皇后区有间公寓
Jimmy's got an apartment in Queens.
好吧  去那里看看能不能找到他
Okay. Head up there. See if you can track him down.
不管昨晚发生了什么  他都参与其中了
Whatever happened last night-- he was a part of it.
别担心  小科斯莫  这些警察是最出色的
Don't you worry, little Cosmo. These guys are the best.
如果有谁能找到你的父母  那就是他们
If anyone can find your folks, it's them.
不过我们又和医院  联调局以及国家失踪儿童中心
Except we have double-checked with hospitals, the F.B.I.,
复核过了  一无所获
and the N.C.M.E.C., and nothing.
如果有人丢了孩子
If someone was missing their baby,
难道不会报案吗
wouldn't they have come forward?
也许他们不知道他失踪了
Maybe they don't know he's gone...
也许他们都死了
Or maybe they're not alive.
我们也不知道那晚发生了什么
I mean, we don't know what happened that night.
不管发生了什么  都发生在那座教堂附近
Well, whatever happened, happened near that church.
蕾妮  你来干什么
Lanie, what are you doing here?
我有些线索  想着过来
I had some information. I thought I'd come by
看看我的小病人
and check on my little patient.
嗨  小甲虫
Hi, you little doodle bug.
你好吗
How you doin'?
你为什么觉得卡梅隆是在教堂附近中枪的
What makes you think Cameron was shot near the church?
根据伤口的性质和
Well, based on the nature and the severity
严重程度  死者中弹后可能只活了
of the wounds, your victim maybe had
五到十分钟  就流血身亡了
only five or ten minutes before he bled out.
他没法开车开那么远
He couldn't have driven that far.
最多20个街区
20 blocks at most.
我还在他的指甲下发现了特别的东西
I also found something unusual under his fingernails.
蜡渣  烧焦的硝化纤维
Wax residue, charred nitrocellulose...
和樟脑
and camphor.
-硝化纤维  -对
- Nitrocellulose? - Yes.
是用来做赛璐珞的
It's used to make celluloid.
老库存胶片中有
You can find it in old film stock,
还有一些塑料  但极其易燃
certain kinds of plastic, but it's highly flammable.
-对吧  -烧焦的赛璐珞
- Isn't it? - Charred celluloid--
那是哪来的啊
Where would that come from?
我可不知道  那是你的工作
Beats me. That's your job.
现在我的工作就是和小宝宝一起玩
Right now my job is to play with the little baby.
是啊
Yes, it is!
吉米的公寓里没人
Jimmy's apartment is empty,
房东好几天都没看见他了
and his landlord hasn't seen him in days.
如果他杀了卡梅隆
Well, if he killed Cameron,
现在可能在逃往墨西哥的路上了
he's probably halfway to Mexico by now.
好吧  我会发一则通告
All right, I'll put out a B.O.L.O. on him,
询问一下他的保释官
check in with his parole officer,
看他有没有已知亲友的名单
see if he's got a list of known associates.
他刚刚从牢里放出来
He just got out of prison.
如果要逃跑  一定需要人帮忙
If he's on the run, he's gonna need some help.
没错  是啊  你先忙着
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, and, uh, while you do that,
我去去就来
I'm gonna duck inside.
彩票在召唤我呢
I feel a quick pick calling my name.
你不是吧
Are you serious?
就两分钟  很快的
Two minutes, okay?
孩子还未出世  你就拿奶粉钱去赌博吗
Two minutes to fritter away your unborn child's future?
与其说是赌博  不如说是投资
Frittering or investing?
你好  我是埃斯波西托探员
Yo, this is detective Esposito.
我要发一则通告  名字叫吉米·沃夫
I need to put out a B.O.L.O. On a Jimmy Wolfins--
不用了  我发现他了
Never mind. I think I found him.
你好啊  吉米
Yo, Jimmy!
别跑
Come here.
49...
9...
36...
你往哪跑啊  伙计
Where you running to, pal?
厉害啊  看到没
Hey! See?
我就说这是个幸运的地方
I knew this place was lucky.
走吧
Come on.
看到那个家伙了吗
Hmm, see that man?
那是一个坏人
That is a bad man.
他会把事情交代清楚
He's gonna confess.
我们就能知道你是谁啦
Then we're gonna know just who you are.
卡塞尔  我可以再试一次吗
Castle, mind if I try again?
当然可以啦
Of course.
给你
Here you go. Hey.
我想了想  还是在外面等吧
On second thought, I'll just wait outside.
好吧
No problem.
-他真可爱  -是啊
- He's cute. - Yeah.
你是故意的是吗  小坏蛋
You did that on purpose, didn't you?
来击个掌吧  干得好
High five. Good job.
沃夫斯基先生
Mr. Wolfinsky,
这个人你认识吗
Do you recognize this man?
从来没见过
Never seen him before in my life.
是吗
Really?
我倒觉得他很像你的老搭档
I think he looks a lot like your old partner--
七年前抢银行的时候
The one who left you to get busted
他丢下你一人  害你被捕
at that bank job seven years ago.
一点印象也没有
Doesn't ring a bell.
这是一个熟练的谎话精
That's a grown-up lying.
你以后会见到很多呢
Get used to that.
那感觉肯定天天侵蚀着你吧
Must have ate at ya, huh?
在牢房里熬过一天又一天
All those nights in the joint.
你在里面吃苦受罪
Knowing you were in there rotting away,
他却在外面自由自在
while he was out there free
就因为那天他把你扔在了银行
because he ditched you at the bank.
我跟检察官说过了  我没有同伙
Like I told the D.A., I didn't have a partner.
就算有  我也不会做叛徒
And if I did, I ain't no rat.
不做叛徒
What about...
做杀人犯吗
a murderer?
卡梅死了吗
Cam's dead?
这么说你们认识喽
So you do know him?
是认识  但这事跟我一点关系也没有
Yeah, okay, but I had nothing to do with this.
你假释出狱那天  他给家里装了安全系统
The day you make parole, he installs a security system,
门上添了新锁
gets all new locks.
他为什么要这么做
Now why would he do that?
因为  我也不知道  我被判刑的时候
Because... I don't know, when I was convicted,
可能跟人说过会让他付出代价的话
I may have told some folks that, uh, Cam will pay.
但那都过去多少年了
But that was years ago.
听着  实际上
Look, the truth is,
那天搞砸的人是我
I was the one who messed up that day.
我在银行里耽误了时间
I got hung up inside.
卡梅已经尽可能地等我了
Cam waited as long as he could--
他其实早就该走了
Longer than he should've.
我跟他讲过这话  他知道我不记恨他
I told him that. He knew we were square.
卡梅的同事可不是这么说的
Witnesses at Cam's work say otherwise.
他说你们两个吵过架  而且在那之后
Said you two were fighting, that afterwards...
他晚上都不敢回车库
Cam was scared to come back to the garage at night.
什么  才不是呢  我在尝试开始新生活
What? Nah, it's just, I'm trying to get my life together,
就像他那样
like he did.
我本想让他在老板面前说说好话
I thought maybe he could put in a word with his boss,
帮我找个司机的工作
help me get a job driving.
那就有意思了
Well, that's funny.
目击者说你们的谈话后来升级为争吵
'cause witnesses say that the conversation was heated.
因为他不肯帮我
Because he wouldn't help me.
他说不想再跟我有任何瓜葛了
He told me he couldn't be around me anymore,
他不想再跟过去有什么牵连
that that part of his life was over.
毕竟他还欠我一个人情
After all I'd done for him,
当年我没把他供出来
keeping my mouth shut
过了这些年  他连句好话也不肯替我说
All those years, he couldn't even put in a good word?
那是我最后一次见他
That's the last I saw of him.
沃夫斯基先生  昨天晚上你在哪
Mr. Wolfinksy, where were you last night?
跟我女友在泽西
I was with my girlfriend out in Jersey.
我整个礼拜都跟她在一起
I've been with her all week.
那么今天早上呢  六点到七点之间
What about this morning, between 6:00 and 7:00?
我们在一家餐厅吃早饭
We were having breakfast at a diner.
在场的人可以作证
People saw us.
听着  我发誓不是我干的
Look, I swear this wasn't me.
你以前见过这个婴儿吗
Have you ever seen this baby before?
没有
No.
婴儿跟这事有什么关系
What's a baby gotta do with this?
他说的是实话
Well, he's telling the truth.
根据他女朋友和室友的证词
According to his girlfriend and a roommate,
过去几天  他一直待在他们泽西的公寓里
he spent the last few days at their apartment in Jersey.
餐厅的服务员也证实
And a waitress at that diner
案发的时候他确实在那儿
places him there during the shooting window.
好吧  如果吉米说的是实话
Okay, well, if Jimmy was telling the truth,
那卡梅没理由害怕他啊
then Cam didn't have any reason to be afraid of him.
他为什么不敢在3点休息的时候回车库呢
And why was he avoiding the limo garage 3:00 a.m. lunch break?
也许他不是不敢去
Maybe he wasn't avoiding it.
而是因为别的事情
Maybe something else was going on.
大部分的豪车公司都会在车上配备定位装置
Most limo companies use G.P.S. Services to track their vehicles.
也许能查到卡梅那些晚上去了哪里
Maybe they can tell us where Cam was going all those nights.
这就去找
On it.
打扰一下  是贝克特探长吗
Uh, excuse me, Detective Beckett?
-我是   -你好
- Yeah. - Hi.
我是桑德拉·惠特曼  儿童福利中心的
Sandra Whitman-- child services.
很抱歉我来晚了
Sorry it took me so long to get here.
每年这个时候总是特别忙
This time of year is always bad.
没关系  不要紧
Oh, no, uh, not a problem.
宝宝在休息室
He's right in the lounge.
好的  谢谢
Oh, great, thanks.
你们打算拿他怎么办
Um, uh... what's gonna happen to him?
郡相关机构床位已经满了
County facilities don't currently have any beds.
我们会帮他找一个寄养家庭
So we're working to find a foster family to take him.
等安排好了就通知你们
I'll let you know as soon as we do.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们也许不该把他交给陌生人
I don't know if we should just be handing him over to strangers.
卡塞尔  今早之前我们对他来说也是陌生人呢
Castle, we were strangers until this morning.
面对那么一张小脸  你怎么还这么理性啊
How can you be logical in the face of that face?
因为我必须这样
Well, because I have to be.
我们也不知道科斯莫最后会怎么样
I mean, we don't know what's gonna happen to Cosmo.
不能投入太多感情
We can't get attached.
所以你才一直不肯抱他吗
Is that why you won't hold him?
是的
Yes.
好吧  我坦白
Okay. Fine.
我一直不太喜欢孩子
I've never really been a baby person.
有些人一看见宝宝
I mean, some people see babies
就想抱抱啊  啃啃小脚趾头啊什么的
and they want to hold them, they want to nibble their toes,
我从来都不像他们那样  所以
and I've never been one of those people. So...
我倒不知道你还有这一面
I did not know that about you.
你一定也讨厌彩虹吧
I suppose you hate rainbows, too.
我不讨厌宝宝  卡塞尔
I don't hate babies, Castle.
我只是没觉得他们那么可爱
I just don't see the appeal.
但等我们有了自己的孩子
But I'm sure I'll feel differently
我肯定会有所改变的
when we have one of our own.
是吗
Will you?
你会吗
Will you?!
我们提取了之前六个晚上
Okay, so we pulled G.P.S. information
卡梅隆工作期间的定位信息
from the past six nights that Cameron was at work,
没发现有什么异常
and nothing out of the ordinary.
但是他休息的时候就不一样了
Until we took a look at his lunch hour.
-你看  -每天凌晨三点
- Check it out. - Every night at 3:00 a.m...
他交班之后  都会开往这里
he'd go off shift, and he would drive here.
市中心的考弗斯大厦
The Colfax building downtown?
但他不会待很久  看着
But he wouldn't stay long. Watch.
每天晚上  他都会开往同一个地方
Every night, he would drive to the same destination...
位于字母城的一个街区
A block in Alphabet City.
每天晚上他都选择不同的路线
Each night he would take a different route,
一次又一次的重复尝试
and he'd do it over and over again.
他这样的人干这种事
Only one reason I can think why someone like him
我只能想到一个原因
would be doing something like that.
他是在练习逃跑路线
He was practicing escape routes.
卡梅又重操旧业了
Cam was back in the life.
他在计划逃跑
He was planning a getaway.
我们看了考弗斯大厦的交通摄像头的录像
We scrubbed traffic cam footage from the Colfax Building
从那晚卡梅隆离开家开始
between the time Cameron left his house that night,
-到他到教堂为止  -我们在大厦后面
- to when he arrived at the church. - And we found this
发现了这段录像
behind the Colfax Building.
那是他的车
That's his car.
有两个人跟他在一起
Two guys are with him.
凌晨3点57分
3:57 a.m.
他们带着那个箱子去哪
Where are they going with that briefcase?
不知道  但是
Don't know, but then...
大概15分钟之后
about 15 minutes later...
他们又出现了  同一个箱子
Here they come. Same briefcase.
这是一次抢劫...
It's a heist...
而卡梅是他们的司机
And Cam is the wheelman.
-那栋楼里有什么  -高级办公室
- What's in the building? - Uh, high-end offices,
珠宝店  房地产公司  还有律师事务所
Jewelry store, real estate, and law offices,
电视台  和几家银行
The TV station, and a couple of banks.
我查过记录
I checked the blotter.
那个地址没有人上报
There were no reports of any break-ins
入室抢劫案
from anyone at that address.
他们也许不知道他们被抢了
Well, they might not know they have been hit.
录像里有那个婴儿的迹象吗
Is there any evidence of the baby in the footage?
没有  只有三个男人和一辆野马车
Nope. Only three men and a mustang.
那科斯莫是从哪来的
So where did Cosmo come from?
一定是从卡梅隆凌晨4点12分
Must be from wherever Cameron was between 4:12 a.m.
到6点半他中枪之间去的地方来的
and when he was shot at 6:30.
盘查字母城
Canvass the area in Alphabet City
卡梅隆逃跑路线的终点
where Cameron's practice route ended.
看看能否找到那些人的老窝
See if you can figure out where those guys were holed up.
我和卡塞尔去考弗斯大厦
Castle and I will head down to the Colfax Building.
那里一定有人知道那些人拿走了什么
Someone down there must know what these guys took.
抱歉  探长  作为安全主管
I'm sorry, Detective. As head of security,
我跟所有的租客确认过
I checked with all our tenants.
据我们所知  什么都没丢
As far as we can tell, nothing was taken.
什么都没丢  你确定吗
Well, nothing? Are you sure?
丹尼斯先生  你们的安保系统如何
Uh, Mr. Dennis, how--how's your security system?
非常先进
State of the art--
全方位摄像头覆盖  运动检测器
Good camera coverage, motion detectors.
我们仔细检查了整个系统
We double-checked all our systems.
没有被切断的线  没有被触发的警报
No wires were cut, no alarms were triggered,
没有被呼叫的电梯
No elevators called.
就是没有任何有人进入大厦的迹象
There's just no evidence of anyone entering the building.
那你怎么解释这个
Then how do you explain this?
两个戴着面具的男人在凌晨四点
Two masked guys entering your parking lot
进入你们的停车场
4:00 a.m.?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能他们没能通过停车场的大门
It's possible they never got past the parking gate
然后就放弃了
and just gave up.
但我们还是需要检查
Still, we're gonna need to examine
-昨晚的所有监控录像  丹尼斯先生  -当然
- all the surveillance from last night, mr. Dennis. - Of course.
我再给你们一份租客名单
I'll also get you a list of our tenants,
如果你们想跟进的话
if you want to follow up.
一场什么都没拿的抢劫
A heist where nothing was taken.
也许这就是典型的
Maybe this is a classic
"盗而无道"的情况
"no honor among thieves" situation.
抢劫出了问题  他们打起来了
You know, heist goes wrong, they fight.
怎么会有人中枪后还带着个婴儿逃走
Where someone gets shot running away with a baby?
非典型"盗而无道"的情况吗
Not-so-classic "no honor among thieves" situation?
不
No.
早些时候的事让我一直在想
Hey, earlier just got me thinking,
我们的孩子下个月就要生了
our baby's due in a month,
这我无法阻止  如果我还没准备好呢
And I can't stop it. What if I'm really not ready?
你是没准备好
Well, you're not ready.
-什么  -没人能准备好
- What? - Nobody is.
听着  当爸爸就像当警察一样
Look, being a dad is like being a cop.
他们在警校里教你的是什么都没用
It doesn't matter what they teach you in the academy,
你在街上学的才有用  你干得挺好的吧
you learn on the streets. You did okay with that, right?
我的第一天  我紧张得要死
Uh, my first day, I was so nervous,
我跟反恐特警组的车追尾了
I rear-ended a S.W.A.T. van,
然后十个穿着防弹背心的人冲出来
and ten guys in vests poured out,
打算直接把我放倒
ready to take me down with extreme prejudice.
好吧
Well...
你很在乎
You care.
这已经让你比我爸爸要好一百倍了
That already makes you a hundred times better than the dad I had.
就是这里了
This is it.
这就是卡梅的路线的终点
This is where Cam's route ended.
埃斯波  看看这个
Hey, Espo. Check it out.
一个弹孔
A bullet hole.
这栋楼按计划在月底拆毁
The building's scheduled to be torn down the end of the month.
所以成了完美的藏身之处
Making this a perfect hideout.
这里
Over here.
我们觉得杀卡梅的人是在这里开枪的
We think this is where Cam's killer fired from.
那是火药残留吗
Is that powder residue?
也许在冲卡梅隆开枪之前
Probably broke the window with his elbow
他用胳膊肘打破了窗户
before firing down at Cameron.
这栋楼离教堂的距离开车只要五分钟
This building is about a 5-minute drive to that church.
这里最近有什么东西着火了
Something caught fire here recently.
就不久之前
Very recently.
这里还有打斗的痕迹
There's also signs of a fight--
墙上有四溅的血迹  不知道是谁的
Blood spatter on the walls. Don't know whose.
我们还发现了这个
And we found this.
科斯莫到过这里
Cosmo was here.
好吧  卡梅隆一定是在这里得到他的
Okay, so this must be where Cameron got him from.
一个婴儿怎么会在这里
What was a baby doing here in the first place?
让鉴证组仔细搜查这里
Get C.S.U. Down here. Have them tear this place apart.
指纹  痕量证据  任何能帮我们查明
Prints, trace, anything that'll help us identify
-其他涉案人员身份的东西  -好
- whoever else was involved. - Right.
你还好吗
You okay?
还好  我只是在想那个藏身所墙上的
Yeah. I just keep wondering about whose blood that was
血迹是谁的
on the wall of the hideout.
每次我想的时候  故事的结局都不好
Every time I think about it, I don't like how the story ends.
我已经联系了考弗斯大厦里的
Well, I've contacted every business
每一家商户
in the Colfax Building.
没有丢失物品也没有失踪的婴儿
No thefts and no missing babies.
我们又查了一下吉米·沃夫斯基
Hey. We took another look at Jimmy Wolfinsky.
就算他参与了  我们也找不到联系
If he is involved, we can't find a connection.
我又跟卡梅隆的妻子谈了一次
I spoke to Cameron's wife again.
他生活中并没有出现什么新朋友
There's no indication of any new friends in his life.
但他们有财政问题
But they were having money issues.
他们就快要失去他们的房子了
They were on the verge of losing their house.
所以不管他做什么都是为了钱
So odds are, whatever he was doing was for the money.
但他的通话记录没有什么异常
But there was nothing unusual in his phone records,
而且那晚没有通话记录
and no activity that night.
鉴证组刚刚开始工作
Well, C.S.U. is just getting started,
我们要明早才能得到进一步的消息
and we're not gonna learn anything more until tomorrow,
-所以...  -好吧
- So... - All right.
-晚安  -晚安  伙计们
-Good night. - Good night, guys.
我们也该走了
We should probably get going, too.
要知道  尽管卡梅隆中了枪
You know, even though he had been shot,
他还是尽可能地保护婴儿的安全
Cameron did everything he could to keep that baby safe.
那不像是一个坏人的行径
That doesn't seem like the actions of a bad guy.
对  他也许不是个坏人
Yeah, well, he's probably not a bad guy.
他只是做了个坏选择而且被它控制了
He just made a bad choice and got in over his head.
走吧  我们回家吧
Now come on. Let's go home.
嘘  没事的
Shh, it's okay.
没事的  嘘  嘘
It's okay, shh. Hush, hush, hush.
怎么了  科斯莫
Oh, no. What's wrong, cosmo?
-你还在这里  -对
- You're still here? - Yeah.
我一直在找一个寄养家庭
I've been trying to locate a foster family.
但因为这是感恩节周
But because it's Thanksgiving week,
没人能帮忙
no one's available.
我要把他送到郡危机中心去
I'm gonna have to bring him to the county crisis center
直到我找到能带他回家的人
until I can find someone who can take him.
你不是说那里没有床位了吗
I thought you said there weren't any beds.
人满为患时  就得让孩子同床
When it's this crowded, they have to double up.
没有别的选择了吗
There's no other options?
那是能收容婴儿的唯一地方
That's the only place that can take an infant.
如果我们带他回家呢
Well, what if we take him?
等等
Wait...
什么
What?
我们已经很熟悉了  我什么都有
Well, we've already bonded. I-I got all the stuff.
不  卡塞尔  我跟你说过了
No, no. Castle, I told you.
我知道  你还不习惯身边有孩子
I know, I know. You haven't been around babies that much.
没什么大不了的
Not a big deal.
我搞得定  我是婴语者
I got this. I'm the baby whisperer.
她不会就这么给你个小宝宝
Look, she's not gonna just give you a baby.
我肯定会有背景调查
I'm sure that there are background checks
和填一堆的表  对吧
and forms that we have to fill out, right?
如果纽约警察官方监管
Not... if the baby officially remains
就不需要了
in the custody of the N.Y.P.D.
你俩目前为止
And you guys have done...
都表现不错哟
an amazing job so far.
你觉得怎么样  贝克特
What do you say, Beckett?
想要个宝宝吗
Wanna have a baby?
来嘛  肯定很有趣
Come on! It'll be fun.
抱歉
Sorry.
太没有趣了
This is so not fun.
卡塞尔  如果你想用这种方式
Castle, if this is a part of your plan
把我变成爱孩子的人
to turn me into a baby person,
可一点都没作用哦
it's not working.
我没有
It isn't.
一开始是这么想的  但是
Well, it was, at first. But...
他在局里的时候多乖啊
he was so good at the precinct.
我还以为你是"婴语者"呢
I thought you were the "Baby whisperer."
我就是
I am.
是宝宝出了问题
There's something wrong with this baby.
好吧  这里说
Ooh, okay! So, it says here that,
"轻轻地摇宝宝  可以让他安静下来"
"Gently bouncing your baby should calm him or her down."
好了  好了
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
有主意了
I got an idea.
嘘  嘘  好了
Shh, shh, okay.
你让我很难堪啊  宝宝
You're making me look bad, kid.
你想要啥都行  小家伙
Anything you want, okay, buddy?
告诉我  我就给你
You just tell me what it is, I will give it to you.
好了  嘘
Okay, shh.
坐  摇吧
Here, sit. Bounce.
还真有用
Ooh, it's working.
你真是天才
Yeah. You're a genius.
别笑
Do not laugh.
我没笑
I'm not laughing.
不许笑  给我纸巾
You do not laugh. Get me the towel.
给你
Okay, here.
抱着他
Here, take him.
Take him. Okay.
谢了  给你
Come on. Thank you. Here we go. There we go.
-好啦  -地毯不行
- Here we go... - Not on the rug.
我们去...
Okay. We're gonna go up--
椅子不行
Not on that chair.
把他放毯子上  我讨厌那条毯子
Put him on the blanket. I hate that blanket.
我们到讨厌的毯子上
We're going on the nasty blanket.
很好
Yeah, okay, good.
-把住他  会掉下来的  -遵命
- Hold him, or he'll roll off. - Yes.
卡塞尔  我觉得他需要换身衣服
Castle, I think he needs a change of clothes.
帮他脱掉衣服  我去拿套新的
Uh, get him undressed. I'll get a onesie.
换衣服  换衣服
Changin', changin'...
尿布
And a new diaper.
换人
Uh, all right, switch.
给
Here.
纸巾
Wipes.
润肤露
Lotion.
尿布
Diaper.
衣服
Onesie.
接着
And...
就是胜利
victory.
我们成功了
We've done it.
好了
All right.
-抱着他  -好的
- You hold him. - Okay, all right.
给你  我来处理这个
There we go. I'll take care of... this.
里克叔叔很逗吧
Uncle Rick's pretty funny, huh?
我觉得你也好逗
I think you're pretty funny, too.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
好吧
All right.
现在我们要做的就是把他哄睡
Now all we have to do is get him to sleep.
你是个饿饿的小男孩
Well, you are a hungry boy.
是的  你是
Yes, you are.
你真幸运
Good for you.
看啊  谁醒了
Oh, well, look who's up.
我是多久没回家了
How long have I been gone?
连咖啡都没用
Coffee's not even helping.
忘记这码事儿了
I'd forgotten about this part.
你们两个好像被送奶车撞了一样
You two look like you got hit by the milk truck.
看到这张脸没有
You see this face?
这就是你以后的脸
This is the face of your future.
这么糟啊
That bad, huh?
不  不  不  我们睡得像婴儿一样
No, no, no, we slept like babies.
是啊  一个小时醒一次
Yeah, up every hour.
小家伙在哪儿呢
Where is the little guy?
玛莎和阿丽克西斯主动提出要照料他
Martha and Alexis offered to babysit him.
她们说要搞个照看宝宝日
They said they're gonna make a day out of it.
我们那个什么查得怎么样了
So, where are we on, um...
-儿童服务机构  -对  儿童服务机构
- Child services? - Child services.
还是没人上报失踪婴儿
Still no reports of a missing baby.
不过在你们哄宝宝的时候
But while you two were bouncing junior on your knee,
鉴证组的报告出来了
C.S.U. reports came in.
不管凶手是谁  清理了现场
Whoever was there cleaned up after themselves.
现场没有指纹
The place was wiped down for prints.
枪击呢
What about that fire?
分析报告显示烧伤处有高浓度的
Analysis of the burn showed high concentration
硝化纤维和樟脑
nitrocellulose and camphor.
烧焦的赛璐璐
Charred celluloid.
-和卡梅隆身上的一样  -我们发现的血迹
- Just like on Cameron. - That blood we found--
根据基因标记
According to genetic markers,
和这个宝宝有血缘关系
came from someone related to that baby.
但是没有其他的信息
But without anything else to go on,
我们只知道他们有血缘关系
all we know is that they are related.
还是不知道他们是谁
We still don't know who either of them are.
卡梅隆呢  他肯定知道
What about Cameron? He must've known.
我们又查了一遍他的手机  朋友
We rechecked his phones, friends,
和财务情况
and financials.
不管发生过什么  他隐藏的很好
Whatever was going on, he hid it well.
由于办公楼里没人知道
And since no one in that office building
这帮劫匪的目的是什么
knows what our thieves were after,
我们又回到原点了
we're back at square one.
也许不是
Maybe not.
为啥  你想到了什么
Why? What are you thinking?
考虑到我们昨晚
I--given how much baby garbage
搞出的那些婴儿垃圾
we generated in just one night,
和他们在枪击之后的清理
and how quickly they cleaned and vacated that apartment
和撤退速度
after the shooting,
我在想他们把垃圾扔哪儿了
I'm wondering where all their garbage went.
你把我带到了最有风情的地方
You take me to the most exotic places.
如果你不想进来
Look, if you didn't wanna jump in,
可以在旁边等啊
you could've just waited on the side
像以前一样
like you usually do.
啥  你在开玩笑吗  经历了昨晚
What? Are you kidding? After the puke storm
让你深陷其中的呕吐风波
I put you through last night,
不参与进来感觉很不对啊
it felt wrong not to participate.
是哦
Yeah.
顺便说一下  你昨晚很棒
Which, by the way, you were great last night.
谢谢  你也不赖啊
Thank you. You weren't so bad yourself.
我不是什么婴语者
Well, I was no baby whisperer.
我得说  当我主动要求
You know, I-I gotta say, when I--when I volunteered
收养科斯莫的时候  我以为是为他好
to take Cosmo, I-I thought I was doing it for his benefit.
但是我发现  我更是为了自己
But... I realized I was doing it more for mine.
阿丽克西斯还小的时候
I... when Alexis was little,
梅瑞狄斯经常不在家
Meredith really wasn't around.
都是我自己照顾她
So I-I did it all on my own.
当你说你不喜欢小孩子的时候
And when you said you weren't a baby person--
好的  好的  我明白了
Oh, okay, okay. I get it.
-你在想  -是的
- You were thinking that... - Yeah.
告诉你吧
Okay, well, I'll tell you what.
等到那一天
When the time comes...
我绝不可能让你
There's no way I'm gonna let you
一个人照顾我们的孩子
take care of our baby on your own.
伙计们
Hey, guys!
找到了
Got somethin'.
尿布
Diapers.
和科斯莫被我们发现时穿得一样
Same kind that Cosmo was wearing when we found him.
便宜不可降解型的
Cheap, non-biodegradable kind?
简直是犯罪
Well, that's just criminal.
袋子里还有什么
What else is in the bag?
葡萄酒保存套装
Wine preservation kit, with,
和氩气罐
uh, ooh, argon canisters.
真的吗  可真奇怪
Really? That's weird.
乒乓球  球拍和桌网
Ping pong balls, paddles, and a net.
乒乓球
Ping pong balls!
那就是用赛璐珞做的  十分易燃
Those are made of celluloid, highly flammable.
所以才会有那些烧痕
That's what caused the burn.
说真的  他们烧乒乓球做什么
Really? They were lighting ping pong balls on fire?
把这些交给鉴证组  看能否提取出指纹来
Okay, get the bags to C.S.U. see if they can pull prints.
这有一张三天前的收据
Oh, look, a receipt from three days ago
有人从便利店购买了尿不湿
for the diapers from a quick mart.
现金支付
Person paid cash.
有时间标记吗
Does it have a time stamp?
这就是了  下午2:47
Here it is. 2:47 p.m.
我们要找的人出现了
And there's our buyer.
快转头
Turn your head.
快啊  转头啊
Come on, come on.
可恶
Damn it.
葡萄酒保存套装  易燃乒乓球
Okay, a wine preservation kit, flaming ping pong balls,
身世不明的婴儿  外加无人遭窃的盗窃案
a missing baby, and a heist where nothing was taken.
好像我们每取得一点进展
I mean, each time we find a piece of this puzzle,
整个案件似乎就更加无解
it makes less and less sense.
我们肯定漏下了什么
There's something we're missing.
-肯定有什么  -快看快看
- Something that-- - Oh, oh!
开始了  开始了开始了
It's time. It's time! It's time!
有什么东西能把这一切解释得通
Something that's gonna make all the pieces fit.
都安静  大伙儿
Shh, shh, shh, quiet, everybody!
开始了
It's starting!
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
莱恩
Wow, Ryan.
-你买了多少注...  -住嘴
- How many of these things did you buy-- - Shh!
我这是给我孩子攒学费
Baby needs an education.
各位好  我是米兰达·瓦尔
Hello! I'm Miranda Vail,
这里是五州魔法球大奖的开奖现场
and this is the 5 state magicball lottery.
今晚我们的奖池奖金达到史上最高值
We have the largest pot in 5 state history...
我们遗漏的线索  我知道是什么了
That something we're missing? I think we just found it.
-借过  简  -高达两亿4700万美元
- Sorry, Jen. - 247 million dollars.
大奖花落谁家  让我们拭目以待
So let's see if there's a winner out there.
可能就是你哦
You could be next.
你准备好梦想成真了吗
Are you ready for your dreams to come true?
准备好啦
Yes.
现在开始摇奖
Here we go...
40...
我这张上有
I've got that.
9...
-又是我这张上的  -是吗
- Another one. - Yeah?
22...
17...
37...
魔法球号码是
And the magicball number is...
28.
不可能
No way.
28.
-怎么可能  -我是米兰达·瓦尔
- What the-- - I'm Miranda Vail...
你怎么知道的  卡塞尔
How'd you know that, Castle?
-卡梅隆手上的彩票  -这就是动机
- It's Cameron's lottery ticket - And it's motive.
埃斯波西托  你说过考弗斯大厦里
Esposito, you said that there was a TV station
有一家电视台
in the Colfax building?
没错  WQTI台
Yeah, WQTI.
这就对了  那起没丢东西的失窃案
Right, the break-in where nothing was stolen?
乒乓球  蜡和氩气
Ping pong balls, wax, gas.
各位  全都能说通了
You guys, it makes perfect sense.
这是一起彩票作弊案
He fixed the lottery.
他们不是去偷东西  是偷天换日
It wasn't a heist. It was an exchange.
他们把官方的奖球换成了
They replaced the official lotto balls
被他们动过手脚的
with the doctored ones,
所以没人发觉有任何东西失窃了
which is why no one knew anything was missing.
他们肯定用氩气注满奖球
They must've filled their lottery balls
然后用蜡封住注射口
with argon gas, sealing the hole with wax.
摄影棚的灯光一照射  温度升高
Under the hot lights of the tv studio,
氩气使假球膨胀
the argon would make the balls expand enough,
无法进入滑道
they wouldn't go in the chute.
只能弹到一边
They would just bounce off.
这样只有没注过氩气的假球才能进入滑道
So only the balls without gas can fit through 'em.
他们肯定做过测试
Yeah, they must've been doing tests,
对注有氩气的假球进行加热
exposing the gas-filled balls to heat sources,
结果离热源太近  乒乓球又十分易燃
and gotten them too close, and celluloid is flammable...
-所以失火了  -全说通了
- That's how the fire started. - It all fits.
只有一种办法能证明
And there's one sure way to prove it.
-17  -不可能
- 17... - No.
-37  -这不可能
-37... - No, no.
-不  这不可能  -结果就摆在那里
- No, this is impossible. - And yet...
你不明白  这根本不应该发生
You don't understand. This can't happen.
奖球都是彩票委员会派人亲手用
The balls are hand-delivered and locked in sealed briefcases
密封上锁的手提箱送到这里
by the lottery commission.
手提箱会放在保险柜里  只有两个人能打开
They're placed in a safe that only two people have access to.
那从保险柜取出手提箱之后
And what happens to the case
进摄影棚之前是怎么处理的
between the safe and the studio?
我们在开奖直播之前
One briefcase is chosen at random,
从九个完全一样的手提箱中随机挑选一个
between nine identical cases just before the drawing.
之后我们从箱中取出奖球
The balls are then removed from the case,
逐个称重测量  然后由专人
weighed, measured, and then placed
带着橡胶手套将其放入开奖机
inside the machine by people wearing rubber gloves.
因此这种情况  根本没有出现的可能
Making this... A statistical impossibility.
这种情况出现的概率就跟...
The odds against this happening are like...
中头奖一样低
Winning the lottery?
录像里他们拿的手提箱
The case that they had with them at the time
只能装下一套奖球
was only large enough to fit one set of balls.
你说过开奖的这套奖球
You said that they set that you used
是随机挑选的  谁负责挑选
was chosen at random. Who makes that choice?
就是开奖主持人  米兰达·瓦尔
Our lottery announcer, Miranda Vail.
但她已经干这行十年了
But she's been with us for ten years.
绝对做不出这样的事
She would never do something like that.
她有孩子吗
Does she have any children?
有  一个男婴
Yeah, a baby boy.
多大了
How old?
大概三个月吧
Maybe 3 months.
她现在在哪
Where is she right now?
她说她不太舒服  刚刚走了
She said she wasn't feeling well. She just left.
好  你待在这  那些奖球是证据
Okay, you stay here. That's evidence.
给我看好那些球
Watch those balls.
太黄了  我还是别开玩笑了
No. Not touching it.
米兰达
Miranda!
米兰达·瓦尔
Miranda Vail!
很抱歉  我有急事
I'm sorry. I'm in a hurry.
请等一下  我们得谈谈
Please, just wait. We need to talk.
-我不能  抱歉  -我们找到了你的孩子
- No, I can't, please. I'm sorry. - We have your baby.
你们找到他了
You have him.
是的
Yes.
-你们找到本尼了  -是的
- You have Benny? - Yes.
太好了  他在哪  还好吗
Oh, my God. Where is he? Is he okay?
-他很安全  -我丈夫呢
- He's safe. He's-- - What about my husband?
保罗  他们把他也劫走了
Paul, they have him, too.
他们三天前打电话给我
They called me three days ago.
谁
Who?
一个男的
A man.
他说我丈夫保罗还有本尼在他们手上
He said they were holding Paul, my husband, and Benny,
如果我报警
And that if I went to the police
或者向任何人求助  他俩全都活不成
or said anything to anyone, he would kill them both.
他的声音你能认出来吗
And did you recognize his voice?
他用了变声器
It was disguised.
他说如果我还想全家团圆
He told me that if I wanted to see my family again,
我就必须按照他说的去做
I had to do exactly as he said.
他让你做什么
And what did he tell you to do?
他说这很容易
He said it was easy.
我只需要按他要求挑选一箱奖球
All I had to do was pick the right set of balls.
他会在开奖当天早上打电话
He would call me the morning of the lottery
告诉我应该挑哪一箱
and tell me which one.
他打了吗
Did he?
昨天早上五点  他告诉我
Yesterday, at 5:00 a.m., he told me to pick
挑左数第三个手提箱
the third briefcase from the left,
如果最后的中奖码和他希望的不一样
and that if his numbers didn't come up,
我就会失去丈夫和儿子
that I would be sorry.
你在电话里听到别的声音了吗
Did you hear anything else?
从背景声里听出什么了吗
Anything in the background?
没有  我只能听出本尼在哭
No. All I heard was Benny crying.
我什么时候能见到孩子  他在这吗
When do I get to see him? Is he here?
有人正带他过来呢
He's on his way in right now.
有件事我还是不太明白
One thing I-I still don't get.
等他们来领奖的时候
When they came forward to collect their winnings,
你就能知道他们是谁了
you would know who they were.
他们又打算怎么逃跑呢
How did they plan on getting away with it?
他们会把保罗和本尼
They were going to hold Paul and Benny
多关几天  直到他们能去取钱
another couple of days, until they could collect their winnings.
他们一旦把奖金转移出国
Once they moved the money out of the country,
就会放了我的家人
they were going to release them.
但是现在
But now...
你能找到他吗
Do you think you can find him?
如果保罗仍是人质  他活不长了
If Paul's still a hostage, he won't be for long.
不管那天晚上绑架他的人之间发生了什么
Whatever happened that night with his captors,
他们的计划都砸了
their plan is blown.
不一定
Not necessarily.
我们刚刚跟彩票局的官员联系过
We checked with lottery officials.
在卡梅隆的尸体被发现了几个小时后
A second ticket with the exact same numbers
纽约市里卖出了第二张
was sold in the city
有着同样号码的彩票
just hours after Cameron's body was found.
代替我们找到的这一张
A replacement ticket.
他们可能还不知道我们已经发现了这一切
They might not know we made the connection
和彩票之间的联系
to the lottery.
毕竟米兰达执行了他们的指令
After all, Miranda did as she was asked.
所以他们也许还会来领奖金
So they may still come forward.
万一他们觉得这样太冒险了呢
What if they decide that it's too risky?
万一他们发现我们知道了呢
What if they discover that we know?
那保罗·瓦尔对于他们来说就只是个负担了
Then Paul Vail will be nothing but a liability,
他们一定会杀了他的
and they will kill him.
那么我们就要在那之前找到他
Then we need to find him before that happens.
鉴证组的人正在重新检查卡梅的车
C.S.U.'s going over Cam's car again.
看能不能找到他的搭档留下的任何证据
See if his partners left any trace evidence.
但是需要时间
But it's gonna take time.
我们现在最缺的就是时间
Time is one thing we don't have.
而且我们面临的挑战很艰巨
And we're facing an uphill battle.
不管这伙是什么人  他们肯定有手艺
Whoever these guys are, they must've been damn good
才能突破那栋大楼的保安系统而且不被发现
to get past that building's security undetected.
等一下  要是他们没那么做呢
Wait. What if they didn't?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我们已经查到他们在考弗斯大楼
We already know they have one person
有一个内应  也就是米兰达
working on the inside of the Colfax building --
但万一他们在那里有俩人呢
Miranda, but what if they have two?
他们需要有个人帮他们绕过大楼的安保系统
They would've needed someone to help them circumvent
躲避摄像头
the building's security system, avoid the camera,
并且改写进门记录
and rewrite all the logs.
唯一能在不被人察觉的情况下做到这些的人
The only person capable of doing that undetected...
就是安保总管
Is the head of security.
他在那栋大楼里上班  我们跟他谈过
He works in the building. We spoke to him.
我们也许已经露底了
We may have already tipped our hand.
除非他也是被人胁迫的
Not if he's being leveraged, too.
我们对他了解多少
What do we know about him?
沃特·丹尼斯  曾在奥尔巴尼[纽约州首府]当过警察
Walter Dennis. Guy's an ex-cop from Albany.
他有没有家人  配偶或是孩子能被人用来胁迫他的
Any family, spouse, or children they can use against him?
没有  这家伙离异无子
No, guy's divorced. No kids.
听着  丹尼斯十年前由于收受贿赂
Listen to this. Dennis got fired from
而被奥尔巴尼警察局开除了
the Albany police department ten years ago for taking bribes.
-他受贿  -没人胁迫他
- He's dirty. - They're not leveraging him.
他跟他们是一伙的
He's in on it.
如果他跟他们是一伙的  那他就知道我们会怀疑他
If he's in on it, then he knows we're onto him.
他也许见到我们带走了米兰达
He would've seen us taking Miranda.
他们现在不会现身了  他们会杀掉保罗的
They can't come forward now. They're gonna kill Paul.
丹尼斯没上班  我们一走他就离开了
Dennis isn't at work. He left right after we did.
他也不在家
He's not at his apartment either.
-他肯定跟保罗在一起  -听着
- No, he's wherever Paul is. - Hey, check this out.
我发现沃特·丹尼斯曾多次打电话
I found a series of calls between Walter Dennis
给罗曼豪车公司
and Roman's limo service.
正是卡梅隆工作的地方
Where Cameron worked.
丹尼斯往那里打过六次电话
Dennis called there six times.
也许是为了策划这次行动
Probably to plan the job.
只不过这些电话不是打给卡梅的
Only they weren't to Cam.
是这两天打的
These were made in the last two days.
那时候卡梅已经死了  那么
After Cam was already dead, so --
他这是打给谁呢
Who was he calling?
好了  走吧  外面没人
Come on. Let's go. It's clear.
走  带上他
Come on. Let's get him.
走吧  瓦尔
Come on, Vail.
时间到了
Time's up.
快点  把他塞进去
Come on. Get him in.
Come on, get him in there.
把他塞进去  塞到车尾箱里去
Get him in, get him in the truck.
把他塞进去
Get him in.
对不起伙计  事已至此  我们别无选择
Sorry, pal. The way things stand, we got no other choice.
还是有的
I think you do.
跪下
Come on on your knees.
我还以为我再也见不到你了呢
I never thought I'd see you again.
保罗
Paul.
本尼在哪
Where's Benny?
他马上就到
He's on his way up now.
干得漂亮
Nicely done.
谢谢  但是卡梅才是真正的英雄
Thanks, but, uh, Cam is the real hero here.
那个司机
The getaway driver?
是啊  完全就是盗亦有道
Yeah, turns out it was a case of "Honor Among Thieves."
保罗把整件事都交代了
Yeah, Paul told us the whole story.
当卡梅的老板罗曼知道了他的情况后
When Cam's boss, Roman, found out about his past,
逼卡梅接下了这份工作
he pressured Cam into the job
威胁他说如果不合作就炒了他
and threatened to fire him if he didn't go along.
他要毁掉卡梅和妻子
He was gonna destroy everything
努力建筑的一切
he and his wife were trying to build.
罗曼向他保证不会有人员伤亡
Roman promised no one would get hurt,
但就在他们把电视台彩票球箱掉包后
but then after the ball exchange at the TV station,
卡梅偷听到罗曼和沃特·丹尼斯的谈话
Cam overheard Roman and Walter Dennis talking.
说什么要窜逃出境完全是胡说八道
That whole leaving the country thing was bull.
他们根本就没准备留瓦尔一家活口
They never had any intention of letting the Vails live.
没错  在他们去领奖金之前
Yeah, before collecting the winnings,
他们计划伪造一场意外  杀掉他们一家三口
they were gonna stage an accident, killing 'em all.
把他们罪行的唯一证人灭口
Silencing the only witnesses to their crime.
卡梅发现真相后  他下不了手
When Cam found out, he couldn't live with it.
他想救我们俩  但被他们抓到了
He tried to save us both. But they caught him.
所以他抱着本尼就跑了
So he grabbed Benny and ran.
他为了我们牺牲了自己
He gave up his life for us.
看看谁来了
Look who's here.
本尼  天啊
Benny. Oh, my God.
我奶奶给他买了几件新衣服
My grandmother got him some new clothes.
伙计
Hey, buddy. Hey.
天啊
Oh, my God.
好消息是
Well, the good news is --
我是说  除了这家人得救了以外
I mean, besides saving that family --
他们准备对这期彩票重新开奖
they are rolling over the lottery.
所以我还有可能赢得那两亿4700万
So I got another shot at that $247 million.
我只要把我的那些彩票碎片粘回去就行了
All I gotta do is tape my tickets back together.
伙计
Oh, dude.
那些垃圾
They, uh...
已经被扔到楼下垃圾桶了  所以
they already took out the trash, so...
我准备让他在垃圾桶里翻上个一个小时左右
I'm just gonna let him swim around the dumpster
然后再叫他出来
for like an hour, then I'm gonna pull him out.
感恩节快乐
Happy Thanksgiving.
也祝你感恩节快乐
Yeah, you, too.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
你知道吗  我觉得我会想小本尼的
You know, I-I think I'm actually gonna miss little Benny.
谁知道呢
Well, who knows?
没准再过几个感恩节
Maybe in a few Thanksgivings from now,
我们也会有几个亲生的本尼满屋子跑呢
we'll have a couple Bennys of our own running around.
如果你俩几年后有孩子
Hey, if you guys have kids in a few years,
我几年后也有孩子
and I have kids in a few years,
他们就可以一起长大了
they can grow up together.
美好憧憬就这样毁了
And it's ruined.
如果我不赶紧回家把火鸡从冰箱里取出来的话
And the turkey will be, too, if I don't get it
火鸡也就毁了  走吧  女士们  麻利的
out of the freezer. Come on, ladies. Chop, chop.
好了
There we go.
这简直是太激动人心了
Ooh. Oh, this is so exciting.
咱们的家庭正在飞速地壮大
Our family is just growing by leaps and bounds.
亲爱的  如果我们保持这个速度的话
If we keep this up, darling,
我们很快就要换个大餐桌了
we're gonna need a bigger table.
再过二十分钟火鸡就能吃了
Exactly 20 minutes till turkey time.
派正在过来的路上
Pi is on his way,
贝克特的父亲刚刚也打过电话来  他马上就到了
and Beckett's dad just called. He'll be here any minute.
太好了  那贝克特人呢
Excellent. And where's Beckett?
凯萨琳
Katherine.
你这穿着是什么呀
What on earth are you wearing?
我的服装啊
My...outfit.
这不是你们的家庭传统吗
Your family...tradition.
关于这个嘛  你知道这件事上
Yeah, uh, you do know I was kidding...
我是在开玩笑的  对吧
about that, right?
事实上  我还真不知道
You know, I actually wasn't sure about that.
所以我在想  如果这还不是卡塞尔的家庭传统的话
So I figured, if this isn't a Castle family tradition,
我们就把它变成新传统
then maybe it should be.
你最好把这身给我穿上  新教徒
Better put this on, pilgrim.